Catalog of the Walt Whitman Literary Manuscripts in The Charles E. Feinberg Collection of the Papers of Walt Whitman, 1839-1919, Library of Congress, Washington, DC.
Published by The Walt Whitman Archive in collaboration with the University of Nebraska-Lincoln Libraries.
- Literary File, 1841-1919, undated (Box 19, Box 20, Box 21, Box 22, Box 23, Box 24, Box 25, Box 26, Box 27, Box 28, Box 29, Box 30, Box 31, Box 32, Box 33, Box 34, Box 35, Box 36, Box 37)
  - Fancies at Navesink, about 1885; loc.00327; xxx.00330; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 48 x 15 cm (Box 27, Folder Fancies at Navesink (1885). Proof Sheets.)
    An oversized proof of Fancies at Navesink, a group of poems first published in 1885. The poems in this cluster are: The Pilot in the Mist, Had I the Choice, You Tides with Ceaseless Swell, Last of Ebb, and Daylight Waning, Proudly the Flood Comes In, By That Long Scan of Waves, and Then Last of All. In this proof, the poems Last of Ebb, and Daylight Waning and And Yet Not You Alone are not separated, and And Yet Not You Alone appears as the final stanza of the first poem. This proof is grouped with two others at the Library of Congress. The proofs have no editorial corrections, but one (pictured here) is signed by Whitman and another contains a note in another hand reading, "from the papers of Walt Whitman given to Mosher by Traubel 1906 ."
  - [A flash of love], between 1889-1890; loc.00197; xxx.00398; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 12.5 x 19 cm (Box 27, Folder A Flash of Love (1889). A.MS. draft.)
    A two-line draft written on the back of an envelope from F. Gutekunst's Imperial Photograph Galleries, with a note by Whitman on front that reads "head and bust WW, taken 1889, fairly good." [A flash of love] would later appear in a revised form in A Twilight Song, first published in 1890.
  - For Queen Victoria's Birthday, about 1890; loc.00198; xxx.00557; poetry prose printed handwritten 1 leaf 24 x 15 cm (Box 27, Folder For Queen Victoria's Birthday (1890). Proof Sheets)
    Proof of For Queen Victoria's Birthday, with correction and note in Whitman's hand. This item is grouped with another proof at the Library of Congress, which includes no annotations in Whitman's hand but features a notation by Horace Traubel at the bottom.
  - [There in the far northwest], 1876; loc.00121; xxx.00285; poetry handwritten 10 leaves 20 x 12 cm, 11.5 x 18.5 cm (Box 27, Folder From Far Dakota's Canons (1876). A.MS.S. drafts.)
    Apparently, two versions of a poem about the death of Custer. On the verso of the second page is A Death Sonnet (see image 14) and on another is A Death Sonnet for Custer (see image 4). The poem was published on June 10, 1876 as A Death Sonnet for Custer.
  - From My Last Years, about 1876; loc.00199; xxx.00494; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 23.75 x 13.75 cm (Box 27, Folder From My Last Years (1876). A.MS. draft.)
    A draft of From My Last Years written in ink on a sheet of stationery, with three lines crossed out with a blue pencil and one of the corrections in blue pencil. From My Last Years was published only once, in Two Rivulets, 1876.
  - From My Last Years, about 1876; loc.04092; xxx.00494; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 5 x 13.25 cm (Box 27, Folder From My Last Years (1876). Printed Copies)
    Written in pencil on a scrap of paper cut from the bottom of a larger sheet to which has been attached a clipping of the poem, From My Last Years, with corrections in the margin. The poem was published only in Two Rivulets, 1876, without these corrections.
  - [Funeral Sounds], about 1888; loc.00200; xxx.00393; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 27, Folder Funeral Sounds (1888). A.MS. draft.)
    Early draft of a poem that was first published as Over and Through the Burial Chant in 1888. It was later published with the title Interpolation Sounds. The poem was written on the occasion of General Philip Sheridan's death in 1888.
  - Going Somewhere, about 1887; loc.00201; xxx.00352; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 15 x 16 cm, 15.5 x 15 cm (Box 27, Folder Going Somewhere (1887). Proof Sheets)
    Proof of 'Going Somewhere,' first published in 1887. This proof has corrections and a note in Whitman's hand.
  - I Saw Old General at Bay, about 1865; loc.00202; xxx.00198; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 27, Folder I Saw Old General at Bay (1865). A.MS. draft.)
    A draft of I Saw Old General at Bay, first published in 1865, written on two scraps pasted together to create one leaf. Part of one scrap has been lifted to show the lines written underneath.
  - If I should need to name, O Western World!, October 1884; loc.00203; xxx.00339; poetry prose handwritten 3 leaves (Box 27, Folder If I Should Need to Name, O Western World (1884). A.MS. draft and printer's instructions.)
    Draft, lightly corrected, of If I Should Need to Name, O Western World! with a brief note containing instructions to the printer. These were probably sent to the Philadelphia Press, where, on October 26, 1884, the poem was first published. Whitman later retitled it Election Day, November, 1884.
  - If I Should Need To Name, O Western World, October 28, 1884; loc.04095; xxx.00339; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 27, Folder If I Should Need to Name, O Western World (1884). Printed Copy—Camden "Post," Oct. 28, 1884.)
    Clipped copy of If I Should Need to Name, O Western World from the Camden, New Jersey, Post, October 28, 1884, with a note in Whitman's hand. This poem was later published with the title Election Day, November, 1884.
  - [I'll trace this garden oer and oer], about 1865; loc.00204; xxx.00734; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 20.5 x 12.5 cm (Box 27, Folder I'll Trace This Garden. A.MS. draft.)
    Written in ink on letterhead from the Attorney General's Office, where Whitman was first employed on July 1, 1865, is a transcription beginning [I'll trace this garden oer and oer]. This is Whitman's transcription, probably from memory, of Johnny's Gone for a Soldier, a ballad popular during the American Revolution and based on the an Irish ballad entitled Shule Agra.
  - [If the red slayer think he slays], about 1865; loc.00205; xxx.00735; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 20.5 x 12.5 cm (Box 27, Folder I'll Trace This Garden. A.MS. draft.)
    This is a transcription of Ralph Waldo Emerson's poem Brahma. Written in ink on letterhead from the Attorney General's Office, where Whitman was first employed on July 1, 1865.
  - Kentucky, about 1861; loc.00206; xxx.00736; poetry handwritten 6 leaves 11.5 x 18.5 cm to 19.5 x 16 cm (Box 27, Folder Kentucky (1861). A.MS. draft.)
    An unfinished poem, entitled Kentucky, the title given three times, with "By Walt Whitman" on one of the pages (see image 3). On one of the pages is a fragment on the Mississippi River, which editors (beginning with James E. Miller, Jr.) have included as the last stanza of Kentucky (see image 1). On the verso of another page is a cancelled portion of a letter about Jesse Whitman's employment, from which the manuscript can be dated 1861 (see image 12).
  - A Kiss to the Bride, May, 1874; loc.00207; xxx.00737; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 12.5 x 10 cm (Box 27, Folder A Kiss to the Bride (May 21, 1874?). Printed Copy.)
    A clipped copy of the poem A Kiss to the Bride pasted on a larger sheet with a note in Whitman's hand reading, "Marriage of Nelly Grant, (Mrs. Sartoris) the President's daughter, May 2nd, 1874 ." The poem was first published in the New York Daily Graphic, May 21, 1874. This clipping appears to from the poem's reprinting, two days later, in the same newspaper.
  - Recapitulation, about 1889; loc.00208; xxx.00603; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 27, Folder Last Words (1889). A.MS. drafts.)
    Draft of an unpublished poem which was also titled, in other manuscript drafts, Last Words and The last. The draft was written on the back of an opened envelope from W. F. Woodruff.
  - Last Words, about 1889; loc.00209; xxx.00603; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 27, Folder Last Words (1889). A.MS. drafts.)
    Draft of an unpublished poem which was also titled, in other manuscript drafts, The last and Recapitulation. The draft was written on the back of a letter from Josephine B. Kirtland.
  - Last words, about 1889; loc.00210; xxx.00603; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 27, Folder Last Words (1889). A.MS. drafts.)
    Draft of an unpublished poem which was also titled, in other manuscript drafts, The last and Recapitulation. The draft was written on the back of a opened envelope from S. S. McClure postmarked December 8, 1889.
  - The last, about 1889; loc.00211; xxx.00603; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 27, Folder Last Words (1889). A.MS. drafts.)
    Draft of an unpublished poem which was also titled, in other manuscript drafts, Last Words and Recapitulation. The draft was written on the back of a letter from R. M. Bucke, dated December 3, 1889.
  - ? Last Words, about 1889; loc.00212; xxx.00603; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 27, Folder Last Words (1889). A.MS. drafts.)
    Draft of an unpublished poem which was also titled, in other manuscript drafts, The last and Recapitulation. The draft was written on the back of a letter from D. H. Kenaga, dated April 9, 1889.
  - Life and Death, about 1888; loc.00213; xxx.00358; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 27, Folder Life and Death (1888). A. MS. Draft.)
    A draft of Life and Death, first published in 1888.
  - Mannahatta, about 1888; loc.00214; xxx.00311; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 20 x 14.5 cm (Box 27, Folder Mannahatta (1888). Newspaper Clipping.)
    A newspaper clipping of the poem Mannahatta on a larger page with corrections and notes in Whitman's hand. This was the second poem that title that Whitman had published (the first Mannahatta, which begins with the words "I was asking...," first appeared in the 1860 edition of Leaves of Grass). This particular poem was first published in the New York Herald on February 27, 1888 and was later included in the Deathbed edition of Leaves.
  - Memories, about 1888; loc.00215; xxx.00324; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 20 x 16 cm (Box 27, Folder Memories (1888). A.MS. draft.)
    A nearly final draft of the poem Memories, first published in 1888.
  - [And here is the great Meteor], between 1850-1860; loc.00216; xxx.00738; poetry handwritten 2 leaves 25 x 18 cm (Box 27, Folder Meteors (1853). A. MS. draft)
    A draft of an unpublished poem, part of which has been connected to the unpublished poem Pictures. The relationship to Whitman's published verse is unknown.
  - My Seventieth Year, about 1888; loc.00217; xxx.00320; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 27, Folder My 70th Year (1888). A. MS. draft.)
    Draft of a poem later revised and published under the title Queries to My Seventieth Year in 1888.
  - My 71st Year, November, 1889; loc.04098; xxx.00384; poetry printed handwritten (Box 27, Folder My 71st Year (Nov. 1889). Printed copies.)
    Two copies of the November, 1889 issue of The Century Magazine, (one full, one partial) which included Whitman's poem My 71st Year. There are a few small notes, probably not in Whitman's hand, which read " Nov 1889 " and "Mark Twain" (Twain's A Connecticut Yankee in King Arthur's Court is also serialized in this issue). Currently, images of only three pages of one of the copies are available (cover, table of contents, and the page on which My 71st Year is printed).
  - My 71st Year, about 1889; loc.00218; xxx.00384; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 18.75 x 20.25 cm (Box 27, Folder My 71st Year (1889). Proof Sheets.)
    A proof sheet of My 71st Year, first published in 1889, with multiple corrections and notations in Whitman's hand. The proof is printed on the verso of a page titled "Principles of the Republican and Democratic Parties."
  - My 71st Year, about 1889; loc.00340; xxx.00384; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 11.5 x 15 cm (Box 27, Folder My 71st Year (1889). Proof Sheets.)
    Proof sheet of My 71st Year with revisions. My 71st Year was first published in 1889.
  - My 71st Year, about 1889; loc.02503; xxx.00384; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 11.5 x 15 cm (Box 27, Folder My 71st Year (1889). Proof Sheets.)
  - My 71st Year, about 1889; loc.02504; xxx.00384; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 11.5 x 15 cm (Box 27, Folder My 71st Year (1889). Proof Sheets.)
  - My 71st Year, about 1889; loc.02505; xxx.00384; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 11.5 x 15 cm (Box 27, Folder My 71st Year (1889). Proof Sheets.)
    Proof sheet of My 71st Year with revisions. This proof has a note by Traubel reading "see notes, Oct. 31, 1889 ." My 71st Year was first published in 1889.
  - My Task, about 1891; loc.00219; xxx.00406; xxx.00566; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 28 x 22 cm (Box 27, Folder My Task (1891). A.MS. draft.)
    Manuscripts of the following four poems, written neatly with slight corrections: My task, L of G's Purport, Death dogs my steps, and For us two, reader dear. All of the verses except For us two, reader dear were fused together and published as one poem entitled L. of G.'s Purport in 1891.
  - The Mystic Cipher, 1887; loc.00220; xxx.00390; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 9.5 x 21.5 cm (Box 27, Folder The Mystic Cipher. A.MS. draft.)
    A draft of a poem later revised and published as Shakspere-Bacon's Cipher in 1887.
  - [Hark! some wild trumpeter—], between 1871-1872; loc.00221; xxx.00272; poetry handwritten 23 leaves largest 37.5 x 20.5 cm (Box 27, Folder Mystic Trumpeter (1872). A.MS. draft and notes.)
    Held together loosely by a cover onto which a scrap of paper was pasted as a label, inscribed by Walt Whitman: "Hark! some wild trumpeter—." On verso of cover: "Advertising book of the Daily Freeman." At head in Whitman's hand: "Original rough draught and Memoranda of Mystic Trumpeter." Three pages of memoranda consist of trial lines and lists of words to be used in the poem. The first page is signed by Whitman. Mostly written in ink on versos of Department of Justice stationery. Many corrections in pencil, indelible pencil, or red ink. The Mystic Trumpeter was first published in 1872.
  - The mystic Trumpeter, January 19, 1873; loc.04099; xxx.00272; poetry 1 leaf handwritten 43.5 x 30 cm (Box 27, Folder The Mystic Trumpeter (1873). Printed copies in Hungarian)
    A copy of the Budapest newspaper Fovarosi Lapok of January 19, 1873 containing Whitman's poem The Mystic Trumpeter in Hungarian and an interview with the poet by Liptay Pal. At the top, written in pencil, are notes in Whitman's hand.
  - Nay tell me not to-day the publish'd shame, about 1878; loc.00222; xxx.00608; poetry printed handwritten 1 leaf 14 x 16 cm (Box 27, Folder Nay Tell Me Not To-Day the Publish'd Shame (Post-1878). Clipping.)
    Clipping from the New York Daily Graphic of 5 March 1873, with handwritten corrections.
  - [Not Meagre, Latent Boughs Alone], May 2, 1887; loc.00223; xxx.00369; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 27, Folder Not Meagre, Latent Boughs Alone (1887))
    A late draft of Not Meagre, Latent Boughs Alone first published in 1887, with Whitman's signature at the bottom and "Camden NJ" and the date, May 2, 1887, written at the top.
  - [Not meagre latent boughs alone], 1887; loc.00224; xxx.00369; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 10 x 15 cm (Box 27, Folder Not Meagre, Latent Boughs Alone (1887))
    Trial lines for Not Meagre, Latent Boughs Alone, first published in 1887. Written at top is "Camden" and the date, April 28, 1887.
  - My Captain, about 1865; loc.00125; xxx.00218; poetry handwritten 3 leaves (Box 27, Folder O Captain! My Captain! (1865). A.MS.drafts.)
    Draft of the poem that would be published as O Captain! My Captain! in 1865, titled here My Captain. On the verso of one page is a portion of A March in the Ranks Hard-Prest, and the Road Unknown with a line through it.
  - [O Earth, my likeness], 1860; loc.00225; xxx.00099; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 20.5 x 16 cm (Box 27, Folder O Earth, My Likeness (1860). A.MS. draft.)
    A draft of the poem first published as Calamus, No. 36 in 1860 (Earth, My Likeness in the final version of Leaves of Grass). A number 8 and a roman number VI are at the top of the page. This manuscript has a vertical line drawn straight through the middle. On the verso is a page of prose in Whitman's hand with "Rel." at the top.
  - Of that blithe throat of thine, about 1884; loc.00226; xxx.00344; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 28 x 22 cm (Box 27, Folder Of That Blithe Throat of Thine (1884). A.MS. draft.)
    Signed, late draft of Of That Blithe Throat of Thine which was published first in January, 1885. On the verso is a letter from Folger McKinney to Whitman dated June 10, 1884.
  - Of That Blithe Throat of Thine, between 1884-1888; loc.02372; xxx.00344; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 27, Folder Of That Blithe Throat of Thine (1884). Proof Sheets.)
    This proof is grouped with other copies of proof sheets that represent different stages of the printing. Of That Blithe Throat of Thine was published first in January, 1885.
  - Of That Blithe Throat of Thine, between 1884-1888; loc.02371; xxx.00344; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 27, Folder Of That Blithe Throat of Thine (1884). Proof Sheets.)
  - Of That Blithe Throat of Thine, between 1884-1888; loc.02370; xxx.00344; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 27, Folder Of That Blithe Throat of Thine (1884). Proof Sheets.)
  - Of That Blithe Throat of Thine, between 1884-1888; loc.02369; xxx.00344; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 27, Folder Of That Blithe Throat of Thine (1884). Proof Sheets.)
    This proof is grouped with other copies of proof sheets that represent different stages of the printing. Whitman has also written instructions to the printer on this proof sheet. Of That Blithe Throat of Thine was published first in January, 1885.
  - Of That Blithe Throat of Thine, between 1884-1888; loc.00227; xxx.00344; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 27, Folder Of That Blithe Throat of Thine (1884). Proof Sheets.)
  - Old Age Echoes, about 1891; loc.00228; xxx.00397; xxx.00407; xxx.00380; xxx.00565; poetry printed handwritten 1 leaf 28.5 x 16.5 cm, 6 x 14 cm attached (Box 28, Folder Old Age Echoes (1891). Proof Sheet.)
    Proof sheet of Old Age Echoes with many corrections written in ink and pencil. Old Age Echoes is a general heading for four poems: Sounds of the Winter, The Unexpress'd, Sail Out for Good, Eidólon Yacht!, and After the Argument.
  - Old Age Recitatives, about 1890; loc.00229; xxx.00380; poetry prose handwritten 1 leaf 30 x 20 cm (Box 28, Folder Old Age Recitatives (1891). A.MS. draft.)
    Draft titled Old Age Recitatives written on the verso of an envelope and a letter (author unknown) stuck together. Beneath the main title and Whitman's signature is another title, Sail out for good, Eidólon yacht! The text of the poem is identical to the published version of Sail Out for Good, Eidólon Yacht! ( 1891 ). Whitman has written a note about Arena magazine's rejection of the poem in the top right margin.
  - An Old Man's Recitatives, about 1890; loc.00230; xxx.00395; xxx.00408; xxx.00406; xxx.00566; poetry prose handwritten 1 leaf 36.5 x 19.5 cm (Box 28, Folder Old Age Recitatives (1891). Proof Sheets.)
    Proofs of four poems pasted together and collected under the main handwritten title An Old Man's Recitatives. The poems included are: Ancient songs reciting (published as Old Chants in 1891 ), Grand is the seen (first published in 1891 ), Death dogs my steps (published as part of L. of G.'s Purport in 1891 ), and For us two, reader dear, first published in 1891. A note in Whitman's hand in the right margin details failed attempts to publish this grouping in Scribner's.
  - Old-Age Recitatives, between 1890-1891; loc.00231; xxx.00380; xxx.00406; xxx.00566; xxx.00408; poetry prose handwritten 1 leaf 30.5 x 16 cm (Box 28, Folder Old Age Recitatives (1891). Proof Sheets.)
    A galley proof of a group of six poems titled Old-Age Recitatives. The poems included are: Sail out for good, Eidolon yacht! (first published in 1891 ), My task (published as part of L. of G.'s Purport in 1891 ), L. of G.'s Purport (only the first two lines of the poem of the same title published in 1891 ), Death dogs my steps (published as part of L. of G.'s Purport in 1891 ), For us two, reader dear (first published in 1891 ), and Grand is the seen (first published in 1891 ). On the verso is a note to the printer.
  - Old-Age Recitatives, about 1891; loc.00232; xxx.00395; xxx.00383; xxx.00380; xxx.00406; xxx.00566; poetry handwritten 2 leaves 28 x 21 cm (Box 28, Folder Old Age Recitatives (1891). Proof Sheets.)
    Proof pages of six poems collected under the general title Old-Age Recitatives. The poems included are: Old Chants ( 1891 ), On, On the Same,Ye Jocund Twain! ( 1891 ), Sail Out for Good, Eidólon Yacht! ( 1891 ), L. of G.'s Purport (only two lines of the twelve-line poem of the same title first published in 1891 ), My task (published as part of L. of G.'s Purport in 1891 ), and For us two, reader dear ( 1891 ). At the top of the first page is a note to the printer in Whitman's hand.
  - Old Age's Lambent Peaks, about 1888; loc.00233; xxx.00375; xxx.00315; xxx.00346; poetry handwritten 2 leaves 33 x 15 cm; envelope 10.5 x 13 cm (Box 28, Folder Old Age's Lambent Peaks (1888). Proof Sheets.)
    An edited proof sheet with three poems: Old Age's Lambent Peaks, A Carol Closing Sixty-Nine, To Get the Final Lilt of Songs, all published first in 1888. In addition to corrections, Whitman has written a note to the printer at the top of the page. Also included is an envelope with "printer's proofs, short poems, Walt Whitman, 1888, (autographic)" written on it.
  - [Put on the old ship], between 1888-1890; loc.00234; xxx.00388; poetry handwritten 2 leaves 25.5 x 22.5, 24 x 15 cm (Box 28, Folder Old Age's Ship and Crafty Death's (1890). A.MS. draft.)
    An early draft written in ink, with a correction in blue pencil, of Old Age's Ship and Crafty Death's, first published in 1890. The draft has the underlined title Old Age's Ship and crafty Death half way down the page. One page is written on the back an opened envelope addressed to Whitman and postmarked Scarborough, December 20, 1888.
  - Old Age's Ship and Crafty Death's, between 1890-1891; loc.00235; xxx.00388; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 28, Folder Old Age's Ship and Crafty Death's (1890). Proof Sheets.)
    Corrected proof of Old Age's Ship and Crafty Death's with notations in Whitman's hand.
  - Old Age's Ship and Crafty Death's, between 1890 and 1891; loc.00236; xxx.00388; poetry printed handwritten 1 leaf (Box 28, Folder Old Age's Ship and Crafty Death's (1890). Proof Sheets.)
  - Old Age's Ship and Crafty Death's, between 1890-1891; loc.02391; xxx.00388; poetry printed handwritten 1 leaf (Box 28, Folder Old Age's Ship and Crafty Death's (1890). Proof Sheets.)
  - Old Age's Ship and Crafty Death's, between 1890-1891; loc.02392; xxx.00388; poetry printed handwritten 1 leaf (Box 28, Folder Old Age's Ship and Crafty Death's (1890). Proof Sheets.)
  - Old Age's Ship and Crafty Death's, between 1890-1891; loc.02393; xxx.00388; poetry printed handwritten 1 leaf (Box 28, Folder Old Age's Ship and Crafty Death's (1890). Proof Sheets.)
  - [An old man's thought of school], about 1874; loc.00237; xxx.00255; poetry handwritten 2 leaves 44.5 x 20.5 cm (Box 28, Folder An Old Man's Thought of School (1874). A.MS. draft.)
    Two composite leaves made from pasting together several scraps of paper containing a draft of An Old Man's Thought of School, a poem Whitman recited in person at the inauguration of the Cooper Public School in Camden, New Jersey, in 1874. On the versos are parts of letters (to Whitman) and notes in Whitman's hand.
  - Old Salt Kossabone, about 1888; loc.00068; xxx.00347; poetry handwritten 1 leaf 28 x 21.5 cm (Box 28, Folder Old Salt Kossabone (1880). A.MS. draft.)
    Late draft of Old Salt Kossabone, first published in 1888, with a note on the verso in another hand (Ellen Terry).
  - Old War-Dreams, about 1881; loc.00238; xxx.00286; poetry handwritten 1 leaf (Box 28, Folder Old War-Dreams (1865-66). Proof.)